We don't have a choice.
We live in a cruel world.
I'm going to drive them out!
No.
Kill them!
Humanity was suddenly reminded that day
of the terror of being at their mercy,
of the humiliation
of being trapped inside a cage.
Eren!
Eren.
Let us pray.
For the solidity of the three goddesses,
Maria, Rose, and Sina.
For our own welfare.
We must not misdoubt the sacred Walls.
These Walls of light
born from the hands of the divine
are made ever more stalwart
through the offering of our faith.
For it is only
the innocence of faithful devotion
that protects us from the Titans.
It, alone, keeps the Titans away from...
A Titan? Here?
No.
Stay away from the Wall.
Stay away!
Looks like he's in control
of himself this time around.
Yes.
But Eren has yet to win against
the Female Titan even once.
If he's transformed, it means
he's got to be ready for the worst.
-He won't lose so--
-Spirit alone can't win a fight.
You experienced that first-hand.
Defeating Annie
will require more!
Level ground!
She's heading for the level ground!
We can't use
omnidirectional mobility gear there!
Split into two teams and go around!
Understood!
Come on!
This is crazy! What are Titans doing here?
Annie.
You always acted like everything
around you was stupid and pointless.
You never seemed interested in anything.
But there are times
when you're full of life.
That's when you show off
those combat skills of yours.
You talked about
how there was no point to it,
but it didn't seem like
you believed that at all.
If anything, you struck me as a bad liar.
Tell me, Annie.
What are you fighting for?
For what cause did you murder people?
Oh, man.
Section Commander.
Even if we do catch the Female Titan,
the city is going to end up in ruins!
That's not our concern.
This is Erwin's decision.
Prepare the capture nets.
Right!
Eren.
No one said anything about this.
Why are there Titans fighting here?
What in the world is happening?
Titans are fighting each other?
Yes. The damage done
to the city is unimaginable.
Scores of civilians and soldiers
have been killed or wounded.
Erwin! Is this the result of your doing?
It is.
I acted entirely on my own authority.
I offer no excuses.
You must have known
what this plan of yours
would have caused in the middle of a city!
Why did you do it?
For mankind's
victory.
Don't give me that!
You're a traitor!
None of the higher-ups will complain
if I execute you right now!
If you wish.
But
you'll be in charge afterward.
Do not let the Female Titan escape.
Peer is in charge of troop deployment.
Beirer is in charge of provisions.
Work with them
-and do whatever it takes--
-Wait! Stop!
Do you really think
this is for humanity's sake?
I have faith it will serve
as a step forward.
Everyone, lower your guns!
Cuff him!
Yes, sir!
Deploy all troops
and focus on aiding
and evacuating the citizens!
-Yes, sir!
Erwin, I'll let the court of law decide
how to execute you.
I'll gladly accept that
once everything is over.
Levi. Stay put.
You don't like pointless death.
You're right. I'm not fond of
causing it or experiencing it.
Those who can't abandon anything
can't change anything.
The ability to give up your humanity
when forced to rise above monsters...
I think that's something Annie can do!
Annie...
Annie!
Annie.
Your dad is always on your side.
I will kill
the Titans.
Every last one...
Eren!
Is he...
-Eren!
-Stop!
I'm not sure Eren
will recognize you right now!
-She's on the Wall!
-She intends to climb over!
Oh, no!
She's getting away!
I won't let her!
Annie.
Fall.
It was wrong of me.
I won't ask for your forgiveness now.
But all I ask of you
is one thing.
Even if you turn
the whole world against you, it's okay.
I will
destroy the entire world!
Even if the entire world
ends up hating you,
just know that
your dad is always on your side.
Oh, no! He's going to eat
the person inside!
Stop, Eren!
Eren!
I'm
free!
So promise me
that you'll come back.
What's he doing?
What the...
They are merging?
Eren!
Don't go eating
our key evidence, you idiot.
Eren.
Mikasa.
Where's Annie?
Damn it!
What the hell? After all this,
we get the silent treatment?
Annie!
Get out there!
Get out there
and pay for what you've done!
Come on! Don't be a coward!
Annie!
Stop.
It's pointless.
Make a wire net!
Let's get this thing underground!
Understood!
If we end up not getting
any information out of Annie,
what will be left?
Nothing but countless casualties,
ruined lives, and unanswered questions,
all for what?
It seems the plan wasn't
much of a success.
No, I'd say the Scout Regiment
is in the clear now.
Just barely.
Let's hope so.
Erwin, we have a number of questions
concerning this operation.
If you believe you knew
the target's identity,
why didn't you ask for
the Military Police Regiment's assistance?
Sir.
Given the likelihood that
the Female Titan has inside accomplices,
it was necessary to involve
only those above suspicion.
But how do you justify the damage caused
to Stohess as a result of that?
Our ineptitude is to blame.
I offer my sincerest apologies.
Apologies won't fix this!
Had we left her unchecked, the Wall
would have been destroyed eventually.
The ensuing destruction
would have been far worse.
I see.
So do you have any proof that
this devastating operation of yours
has helped to prevent
the downfall of humankind?
I find it unlikely that you'll get
anything out of Annie Leonhart now.
Indeed, I doubt we will.
In other words, it was all for naught?
Eren.
Do you feel all right?
Yes.
It's weird how normal I feel.
I guess Annie is still stuck in there?
Yes.
Damn.
That big of an operation, all for nothing.
Annie went that far to
keep her information safe.
Yes. She slipped
right through our fingers.
Eren let her get away.
Isn't that right, Eren?
If it hadn't been for that brief moment...
Yes.
It's true.
I screwed up.
I froze as soon as I saw her.
Armin Arlelt.
Jean Kirschtein.
You're wanted for debriefing.
Right.
I guess we're up first.
See you later then.
Yes.
It actually felt nice.
Having my body come apart
somehow felt refreshing.
So much that I felt like I wanted to die.
Eren!
I don't want to die now.
I'm glad that you came back.
It's too much for me to understand.
Abandoning your humanity
to rise above monsters...
That's the only way to win?
It's the only hope mankind has
to prevail over the Titans.
I think Eren can do it.
I wonder.
Getting rid of the Titans by
becoming that kind of monster,
would that really be
a victory for humankind?
Eat up.
It won't be easy.
However,
I believe mankind has gained
great potential for survival.
There was a time when we never
even imagined humans becoming Titans.
Compared to then, capturing a member
of the enemy is an enormous step forward.
Yes. There are more out there.
And we will go after every last one.
This time, it is our turn to launch
an attack on Titans within our Walls!
The Scout Regiment and Eren Jaeger's
recall to the capital was rescinded,
and the Scouts were placed in charge of
supervising Annie deep underground.
However,
it would take much more time
and many more lives
for humanity to learn
what was holding it prisoner.